Hello everyone and welcome back to another lesson at EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod的另一节课。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And my name is Kathryn and in the spirit of Halloween, we have a Halloween lesson for
我是Kathryn，为了迎接万圣节，我们准备了一节万圣节课程给
you.
你。
Happy Halloween.
万圣节快乐。
It's Halloween.
今天是万圣节。
It's Halloween and this is an elementary level lesson so we're talking about some basic but
今天是万圣节，这是一节初级课程，所以今天我们讲一些基础但
important things today.
重要的内容。
Exactly.
没错。
So, we're not going to preview anything because the dialogue is pretty simple.
所以，我们不打算预览任何内容，因为对话很简单。
So why don't we listen to it for the first time and we'll be right back.
那我们第一次听一下，马上回来。
Trick or treat.
不给糖就捣蛋。
Tom, aren't you a little too old to be trick or treating?
Tom，你是不是有点太老了，还玩不给糖就捣蛋？
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
Where's your Halloween spirit?
你的万圣节精神呢？
Didn't you ever dress up in a costume and go around the neighborhood trick or treating
你难道没穿过戏服，和朋友们一起在社区里玩不给糖就捣蛋
with your friends?
吗？
Of course I did.
我当然玩过。
When I was 10, trick or treating is for kids plus I'm sure people think you're a kidnapper
我十岁的时候，不给糖就捣蛋是小孩玩的，而且我肯定人们会觉得你像个绑架犯
or something running around with kids at night.
或者什么的，晚上带着孩子到处跑。
Whatever.
随便吧。
I'm going next door.
我要去隔壁。
I heard Mrs. Robinson is giving out big bags of M&Ms.
我听说Robinson太太在发大袋的M&M巧克力豆。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So trick or treating.
所以，不给糖就捣蛋。
Ding dong.
叮咚。
Trick or treat.
不给糖就捣蛋。
So, we're going to explain what trick or treating is just in a little bit.
所以，我们一会儿会解释什么是不给糖就捣蛋。
But before we get into it, why don't we take a look at four important words in Language
但在那之前，我们先看看“语言要点”里的四个重要单词
Takeaway.
。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Well, the first one, Marco, is very important because it's the name of this special holiday
嗯，第一个，Marco，非常重要，因为这是这个特殊节日的名字，
that isn't celebrated everywhere.
不是每个地方都庆祝。
It's only celebrated in some places and Americans, I think, love it above all else.
只在一些地方庆祝，而美国人，我觉得，最爱它。
Right.
对。
Yeah, Halloween.
是啊，万圣节。
And this actually comes from All Hallows Eve, right?
这其实来自“万圣节前夕”，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So it's the night of the spirits of the dead.
所以是亡灵之夜。
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
So the day of the dead.
所以是亡灵节。
And as Catherine mentions, it's celebrated in different ways in different countries but
正如Kathryn提到的，不同国家以不同方式庆祝，但
I think probably the United States is one of the few where people dress up and go trick
我觉得可能美国是少数几个人们会穿戏服去玩不给糖就捣蛋
or treating.
的国家。
That's right.
没错。
And Halloween is the last day of October.
万圣节是十月的最后一天。
So October 31st.
所以是10月31日。
And it's a really fun holiday where mostly children dress up in costumes and they ask
这是一个非常有趣的节日，主要是孩子们穿戏服，然后要
for candy.
糖果。
All right.
好的。
So to dress up means to get in a costume?
所以“dress up”意思是穿上戏服？
Right.
对。
Well, you could say dress up to mean a couple of different things but in this case, you
嗯，“dress up”可以指几种不同的事情，但在这里，你
dress up in a costume.
穿上戏服。
So that means you change your clothes so that you're wearing a costume which is maybe a
意思是换衣服，穿上戏服，可能是
witch's costume or a vampire or something scary.
女巫戏服或吸血鬼之类的吓人装扮。
So you would say, he dressed up as a vampire.
所以你会说，他打扮成了吸血鬼。
He dressed up as a vampire or they got dressed up for the wedding.
他打扮成了吸血鬼，或者他们为婚礼盛装打扮。
OK.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
So dress up.
所以是“dress up”。
And then we have the word kidnapper.
然后我们有“kidnapper”这个词。
So the friend is afraid that his friend will look like a kidnapper if he goes out trick
所以朋友担心，如果他跟孩子们出去玩不给糖就捣蛋，
or treating with the kids.
他会看起来像个绑架犯。
And so a kidnapper comes from the word to take or to grab.
“kidnapper”来自“拿走”或“抓住”这个词。
So kid grabber.
所以是“抓小孩的人”。
And that means that you're going to take children from the streets and steal them.
意思是你会从街上带走孩子并偷走他们。
Right.
对。
But you can kidnap an adult, right?
但你也可以绑架成年人，对吧？
So it's not only for kids.
所以不只是针对小孩。
That's right.
没错。
It's for any kind of person who you take without them wanting you to.
它适用于任何你不经同意就带走的人。
So against their will.
所以是违背他们的意愿。
OK.
好的。
Kidnapper.
绑架犯。
And finally, we have M&Ms.
最后，我们有M&M巧克力豆。
What are M&Ms?
M&M巧克力豆是什么？
Not the singer, right?
不是那个歌手，对吧？
M&Ms.
M&M巧克力豆。
No.
不是。
M&Ms is spelled differently, the singer.
M&M巧克力豆拼写不同，那个歌手。
This is a delicious chocolate treat.
这是一种美味的巧克力零食。
It's a candy.
是一种糖果。
And it comes in big brown bags.
装在大棕色袋子里。
And if you want them with peanuts, they come in a yellow bag.
如果你想要带花生的，它们装在黄色袋子里。
You know your M&Ms.
你很了解M&M巧克力豆。
Oh man, I could tell you all the colors.
哦，天哪，我能告诉你所有颜色。
But M&Ms are really delicious.
但M&M巧克力豆真的很好吃。
And it's actually a brand, M&Ms.
而且它其实是一个品牌，M&M巧克力豆。
It's a brand.
是一个品牌。
Right.
对。
So many people probably know it.
所以很多人可能都知道。
But just in case, they're called M&Ms.
但以防万一，它们叫M&M巧克力豆。
Very good candy.
非常好的糖果。
All right.
好的。
So these words were relatively easy and simple.
所以这些词相对简单容易。
So why don't we listen to our dialogue again.
那我们再听一遍对话吧。
Let's slow it down just a little bit.
我们放慢一点速度。
And we'll be right back to take a look at Fluency Builder.
我们马上回来看看“流利度构建”。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
All right.
好的。
We're back.
我们回来了。
So on Fluency Builder, we promised that we were going to look at this word trick-or-treating.
所以在“流利度构建”里，我们承诺要看看“trick-or-treating”这个词。
So let's look at it now.
那我们现在来看。
Trick-or-treat.
不给糖就捣蛋。
It's a verb, right?
它是一个动词，对吧？
To trick-or-treat.
玩不给糖就捣蛋。
And it comes from the words that we say when we're children to the person whose door we
它来自我们小时候敲门时对开门的人说的话
knock on.
。
So for example, I say...
比如，我说...
And then I open the door.
然后我打开门。
I say trick-or-treat.
我说不给糖就捣蛋。
Okay.
好的。
So what are you supposed to do in this when somebody says trick-or-treat?
所以当有人说“不给糖就捣蛋”时，你应该做什么？
Well, I'm a child.
嗯，我是个孩子。
I'm holding my bag.
我拿着我的袋子。
And you're supposed to say, happy Halloween and give me some candy.
你应该说，万圣节快乐，然后给我一些糖果。
Okay.
好的。
All right.
So trick-or-treat means you could either trick someone.
所以“不给糖就捣蛋”意味着你可以捉弄别人。
You could play a trick on them like scare them or put some toilet paper on their house.
你可以对他们搞恶作剧，比如吓唬他们，或者把卫生纸扔到他们房子上。
Or you can give them a treat.
或者你可以给他们款待。
Or accept a treat.
或者接受款待。
And so the idea is if you don't give me a treat, I will do something bad to you.
所以这个想法是，如果你不给我款待，我就会对你做坏事。
I see.
我明白了。
But this doesn't really happen, right?
但这其实不会发生，对吧？
Like when kids go to people's houses, they say trick-or-treat and then they get candy
比如当孩子们去别人家时，他们说“不给糖就捣蛋”，然后他们就会得到糖果，
automatically.
自动地。
Almost automatically, yeah.
几乎是自动的，是的。
Sometimes people avoid the holiday and they close their doors and lock them and they don't
有时人们会避开这个节日，他们关上门并锁上，而且他们不
answer the door.
开门。
And that's when someone maybe throws an egg at the house or does something mean...
那时可能有人会朝房子扔鸡蛋或做点坏事……
Or puts toilet paper on their tree.
或者把卫生纸挂到他们的树上。
Yeah.
是的。
So trick-or-treat is what we say, but it's also something we can do.
所以“不给糖就捣蛋”是我们说的，但也是我们可以做的事。
So we can go trick-or-treating.
所以我们可以去玩“不给糖就捣蛋”。
Go trick-or-treating.
去玩“不给糖就捣蛋”。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
And now we have another phrase here that's a little bit complicated.
现在我们还有另一个短语，有点复杂。
But when the friend answered the door, he said, aren't you a little too old to be trick-or-treating?
但当朋友开门时，他说：“你是不是年纪太大了，不适合玩‘不给糖就捣蛋’？”
All right.
好的。
I like this phrase because it's sarcastic.
我喜欢这个短语，因为它很讽刺。
The person is not asking a real question.
这个人并不是在问一个真正的问题。
He's saying, listen, you are too old to be trick-or-treating.
他是在说：“听着，你年纪太大了，不适合玩‘不给糖就捣蛋’。”
And so in this case, aren't you... is a way to introduce something that we know is true,
所以在这种情况下，“你是不是……”是用来引出我们知道是真实的事情，
that we think is true.
我们认为真实的事情。
It's kind of rude and sarcastic.
这有点粗鲁和讽刺。
So if I say, aren't you supposed to be at work?
所以如果我说：“你是不是应该在工作？”
Oh, shoot.
哦，糟了。
So it's in that form.
所以就是那种形式。
You're not really asking a question.
你并不是真的在问问题。
You're more demanding an explanation.
你更多是在要求一个解释。
Right.
对。
It's a suggestion.
这是一个暗示。
It's like, you're probably supposed to be at work right now.
就像是在说：“你现在可能应该在工作。”
So Marco, aren't you supposed to be at school right now?
所以Marco，你是不是现在应该在学校？
So do we always... but we always use it in that sense, right?
所以我们总是……我们总是用这个意思，对吧？
Aren't you... and then...
“你是不是……”然后……
Yeah.
是的。
Aren't you...
“你是不是……”
Aren't you a little old for that kind of an outfit?
“你是不是年纪太大了，不适合穿那种衣服？”
All right.
好的。
So aren't you...
所以“你是不是……”
All right.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
So those are the two phrases for fluency builder today.
所以这就是今天流利度构建的两个短语。
Let's listen quickly to our dialogue one more time and we'll be right back.
让我们快速再听一遍我们的对话，然后马上回来。
Trick-or-treat.
不给糖就捣蛋。
Tom, aren't you a little too old to be trick-or-treating?
Tom，你是不是年纪太大了，不适合玩“不给糖就捣蛋”？
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
Where's your Halloween spirit?
你的万圣节精神呢？
Didn't you ever dress up in a costume and go around the neighborhood trick-or-treating
你难道没穿过戏服，和朋友们在附近玩“不给糖就捣蛋”
with your friends?
吗？
Of course I did.
我当然做过。
But when I was 10, trick-or-treating is for kids.
但在我10岁的时候，“不给糖就捣蛋”是给小孩玩的。
Plus, I'm sure people think you're a kidnapper or something, running around with kids at
而且，我敢肯定人们会以为你是绑架犯之类的，晚上和孩子们到处跑。
night.
Whatever.
随便吧。
I'm going next door.
我要去隔壁了。
I heard Mrs. Robinson is giving out big bags of M&Ms.
我听说Robinson太太在发大袋的M&M巧克力豆。
All right.
好的。
So, Marco, have you ever trick-or-treated?
那么，Marco，你玩过“不给糖就捣蛋”吗？
I did.
我玩过。
I used to go trick-or-treating when I was little and it was actually really fun.
我小时候经常去玩“不给糖就捣蛋”，其实真的很好玩。
We used to have competitions about who had the most candy.
我们以前会比赛谁得到的糖果最多。
I've heard about this.
我听说过这个。
Right?
对吧？
Because you don't necessarily bring a bag.
因为你通常不带袋子。
You bring a pillowcase.
你带一个枕套。
Right.
对。
And you fill your pillowcase with candy.
然后你把枕套装满糖果。
Now, the interesting thing is that sometimes you wouldn't necessarily only get candy from
有趣的是，有时你不一定只从人们那里得到糖果，
people.
Right.
对。
Sometimes you got weird things like pennies or toothbrushes or apples.
有时你会得到奇怪的东西，比如硬币、牙刷或苹果。
Yeah.
是的。
So you would go to someone's house and they would give you an apple.
所以你去别人家，他们会给你一个苹果。
You'd be like, okay.
你会想，好吧。
But there was always an old lady who lived near, well, she lived in the neighborhood
但总有一个老妇人住在附近，嗯，她住在社区里，
and every neighborhood had one.
每个社区都有这样一个。
All my friends had a lady they would go to and she gave the full-size candy bars.
我所有的朋友都有一个他们会去找的女士，她给的是全尺寸的糖果棒。
Wow.
哇。
Right?
对吧？
Because normally stores sell small candy bars for the Halloween holiday because they're
因为通常商店在万圣节卖小糖果棒，因为它们
smaller, they're cheaper, it's easier to give them to many people.
更小、更便宜，更容易分给很多人。
But there's always one person who has the big full-size candy bars and everyone goes
但总有一个人有大的全尺寸糖果棒，每个人都去
to her.
找她。
Right.
对。
Exactly.
没错。
And actually it's amazing how Halloween is such an important event in the States because
实际上，万圣节在美国是如此重要的活动，真是令人惊讶，因为
everyone dresses up, everyone puts out decorations or pumpkins outside of their homes.
每个人都穿戏服，每个人都在家外放装饰品或南瓜。
They have pumpkin carving contests which are really cool how they carve out pumpkins.
他们有南瓜雕刻比赛，雕刻南瓜真的很酷。
They make faces in the pumpkins and then we can put a candle inside to light it up.
他们在南瓜上刻出脸，然后我们可以放蜡烛在里面点亮它。
It's really fun.
真的很好玩。
So that's called a jack-o'-lantern, right?
所以那叫“杰克灯”，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
Why is it called a jack-o'-lantern?
为什么叫“杰克灯”？
Do you know?
你知道吗？
I have no idea.
我不知道。
It's weird.
很奇怪。
Maybe it's like a person looks like a person's face.
也许是因为它看起来像人的脸。
Maybe a jack-o'-lantern.
也许“杰克灯”。
Because a lantern is a light.
因为灯笼是一种灯。
It's like a light with a candle in it.
就像里面有蜡烛的灯。
It's actually a very fun holiday.
这其实是一个很好玩的节日。
It's really interesting and it's kind of strange when people really oppose it because they
真的很有趣，当人们强烈反对它时有点奇怪，因为他们
say that it has to do with the devil or it has to do...
说它和魔鬼有关，或者和……
It's a pagan ritual and things like this.
这是一种异教仪式之类的东西。
But you know, it's just good fun.
但你知道，这只是好玩。
It's fun.
很好玩。
It's silly.
很傻。
Everyone likes to dress up in a costume.
每个人都喜欢穿戏服。
What was the weirdest costume that you've dressed up as, as an adult or a child?
你穿过的最奇怪的戏服是什么，作为成年人或孩子？
Because I know you've dressed up as an adult as well.
因为我知道你作为成年人也穿过戏服。
I dress up every year.
我每年都会打扮。
I was Pippi Longstocking last year.
去年我扮成长袜子皮皮。
Well, as a child one year, I dressed up as an injured soldier because my dad was in the
嗯，小时候有一年，我扮成一名受伤的士兵，因为我爸爸在
military so we always had fatigues around the house.
军队里，所以我们家里总是有迷彩服。
And so I used his fatigues and I put blood on my face and I had crutches.
于是我用他的迷彩服，在脸上涂了血，还拄着拐杖。
And people thought that I really had a broken leg.
人们以为我真的摔断了腿。
So they used to give me double...
所以他们给了我双倍……
That year they gave me double the candy because they thought, oh, here's a poor girl in crutches.
那一年他们给了我双倍的糖果，因为他们以为，哦，这里有个拄拐杖的可怜女孩。
And trick or treating.
在玩“不给糖就捣蛋”。
And my costume was an injured soldier so they just didn't understand it.
而我的服装是受伤的士兵，所以他们根本没理解。
It's really funny.
真的很好笑。
Nice.
不错。
Well, we want to hear about you guys.
好了，我们想听听你们的故事。
If you go trick or treating or if you dress up for Halloween.
你们是去玩“不给糖就捣蛋”，还是为万圣节打扮？
I know that many places around the world have parties or festivities for Halloween and people
我知道世界上很多地方都有万圣节派对或庆祝活动，人们
dress up.
会打扮。
So come to our website EnglishPod.com.
所以请访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
We'll see you guys there and we'll see you guys next time.
我们会在那里见你们，下次再见。
Happy Halloween.
万圣节快乐。